Lieba Vhutshilo

Midrand. Gauteng. +27 67 172 4999 liebavhutshilo@gmail.com

Digital Marketing | Marketing Communications | Public Relations

49 Maranta street Ebony Park Midrand Gauteng 1632

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

My career span over the period of three years, working with different organisations to execute communications and marketing activities, this exposed me to different communications tools and made me develop good relationship management skills. I can work as an individual and in a team. I Currently work for a Marketing Agency which makes me versatile and can work extra hour. My skills include graphic design, social media management, media relations, events and communications managements.

SKILLS & CORE COMPETENCIES

- Communications
- Report writing
- planning

- Social Media
- Branding
- Stakeholder

- Graphic design
- Digital Marketing
- Computer literacy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Brandlytix

Digital Marketing Assistant

10/01/2022- present

- Manage social media accounts of seven brands by creating content strategy, write posts, schedule posts and design posters
- Respond to social media comments and monitor mentions, shares and likes
- Manage websites by updating it with content, press release, images and design website banners
- Update mailing database which includes the media. Write newsletters, articles and email marketing campaigns to be sent out to the database contacts
- Conduct research, compile reports and do all administration duties including presentations
- Build relationships with clients by sending communications, attend workshops and assist in creating marketing events

Daktari Bush School

Marketing Manager

01/12/2020-01/07/2022

- Develop communications strategies which also include making research of media platforms for publications
- Manage social media accounts by creating content, design images, answer comments, monitor content likes, shares and mentions
- Create marketing campaigns and events, take pictures and videos to use for social media, websites, newsletters and other publications
- Draft newsletters and make sure they are sent out to stakeholders, media, internal staff and industrial community
- Manage branding inventory by ordering new branded materials and make sure they are placed in events
- Manage website by updating it with newsletters, blog posts, images and maintain SEO

Psira

Communications and Events Intern

05/11/2019-31/10/2020

- Write internal communications, newsletters and other publications
- Assist with creating and implementing communications strategies
- Take pictures and videos to be used for different media purposes such as newsletters, media publications, social media and website
- Assist with creating events such as stakeholder events, mall exhibitions, internal workshops, award ceremonies and media interviews
- Manage branding storeroom by keeping record of branded materials, distribute branded materials and make sure the brand is visible in all events
- Maintain stakeholder relations by updating database, send communications such as Annual Reports, events invitations and announcements. And answer stakeholder enquires

Enactus University of Venda

Marketing manager

01/07/2016-31/06/2017

- Manage social media platforms by posting content and designing posters
- Create media and marketing campaigns through advertisements, mall activations and social media campaigns
- Prepare media database and make contact with different media platforms for publications
- Liaise with university executives, community engagement and faculties when creating events and workshops to broaden network
- Manage branding materials such as backdrop, banners and distribute t-shirts and caps to the team as well as placing branded material in events
- Write and send internal communications about project meetings, reports and projects visits

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Arts Media Studies, University of Venda, 2019
- Grade 12, Davhana secondary school, 2014

REFERENCES

- Ms Patience Moripa (Supervisor)
 Daktari Bush School, 2021

 Patience.moripa@gmail.com
 +27 76 598 6072
- Bonang Kleeinbooi (External Communications and Branding Officer/ now Communications Manager)
 Psira, 2020
 Bonang Kleeinbooi@psira.co.za
- Vhonani Madzivhandila (Project Secretary)
 Enactus university of Venda, 2018
 madzivhandilavhonani@gmail.com
 - +27 73 110 6266

+27 82 825 6870